<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jens Jonsson Portfolio</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jens Jonsson Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 13:29:36 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Investigative Reversing 0</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/picoctf_challanges/investigativereversing0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 13:29:36 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/picoctf_challanges/investigativereversing0/</guid>
      <description>Author: Danny Tunitis&#xA;Description We have recovered a binary and an image. See what you can make of it. There should be a flag somewhere.&#xA;Solution First I loaded up the binary in Ghidra. Ghidra gave me some nice C code to work with and I began renaming variables that were obvious, such as arguments to the standard functions and what looked like for loops. This made it much easier to read.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Current Coursework</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/current_coursework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 19:55:05 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/current_coursework/</guid>
      <description>Currently, I am taking a course in applied cryptography and a project course on building a secure network. I will update my website once I have written my reports and documentation.&#xA;For the applied cryptography course, I have coded an implementation of AES in Rust and completed Set 1 of the Cryptopals challenges.&#xA;I will also probably add some writeups for some picoCTF forensic flags once I have time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bachelor Degree Project: Password Generation using ambient sound</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/bachelordegreeproject/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 19:31:10 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/bachelordegreeproject/</guid>
      <description>My bachelor degree project that investigates if using regular ambient sound can be used to generate secure passwords.&#xA;In short: it is not great. Using two computers to record audio simultaneously resulted in one computer showing terrible entropy according to the NIST 800-90B test suite, while the other showed great entropy. When using the recorded audio as an entropy source for our underlying hash-based RNG, our RNG passed the NIST 800-22 tests.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design of a prototype GUI for Vattenfall</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/vattenfallgui/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 19:15:57 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/vattenfallgui/</guid>
      <description>A report, developed as part of a group project for Vattenfall, exploring and designing a prototype GUI aimed at raising awareness of energy consumption and promoting more sustainable usage practices.&#xA;Read the report&#xA;Research and Writing Contributions Eco-feedback Data representation </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Klantboll</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/klantboll/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 18:47:26 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/klantboll/</guid>
      <description> Your browser does not support the video tag. A game made from scratch by a team of 9 students using Scrum.&#xA;The game is about playing as a clumsy football player and picking up power-ups, but be careful some of them are rigged against you! Kick your way to victory!&#xA;Coded in C# and created in Unity.&#xA;Try it out!&#xA;Github&#xA;Game Development Responsibilities Kicking functionality Prototype movement Ragdoll functionality Animation switching Acting Product Owner </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 18:03:32 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>I am currently a student at the Royal Institute of Technology (KTH) in Sweden, working on my masters in Cybersecurity. Prior to my university studies, I worked at &amp;lsquo;Pålgård Söner och Kran AB&amp;rsquo; where I briefly started part time as IT support in their small office right after high school. From my high school studies I obtained a vocational degree as an IT technician.&#xA;After a short period, I was given the opportunity to broaden my role and joined the company as a crane operator fulltime.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
